嗨，媽媽
Hello, mummy.
怎麼樣，兒子？
How are you, son?
我很好
I am good.
學習進展如何？
How are studies going?
一切都很順利
It's going well.
已經開始上課了
Classes have begun.
他的作息時間都亂套了
His routine will be disturbed.
讓他睡覺吧
Let him sleep.
白天那麼長時間你不打電話，非要等晚上才打
You let the day pass and then call specifically at night.
告訴我
Tell me.
你心情怎麼樣？
Are you in good spirit?
還挺好的
Yes, mummy.
這個問題你已經問了無數次了
How do you manage to keep repeating the same question?
好吧
Okay.
那我就掛了
I'll hang up then.
好
Okay.
- 晚安-晚安
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
你是在裏麵改坐標嗎？
Are you revising 'coordinate' inside?
再給我點時間，兄弟
Just two more minutes, bro.
它會掉下來對吧？
Did it fall?
對不對？
早就告訴過你們
Did I tell you or not?
傑圖·拜亞和物理學永遠不會出錯
Jeetu Bhaiya and Physics can never be wrong.
拜亞哥，再來一次
Bhaiya. Bhaiya. Once more.
你交了幾次的錢？
How many times did you pay the fees?
我要是讓你再交一次錢呢？
What if I say 'once more'?
看，他在課堂上犯睏了
Look at that. He is feeling sleepy in class.
我有那麼無聊嗎？
Am I that boring?
我淩晨4:30偷了別人的車
I stole someone's wheel at 4:30 AM.
他隨時都可能來找我
He may show up anytime.
然而這家夥居然睏了
And this chap is all sleepy.
對不起，老師
Sorry, sir.
- 我整晚都睡不著，所以...-你剛才說什麼? 再說一遍？
- I could not sleep all night, so.. - What did you just say? Come again?
- 我整晚都睡不著...-不是這句，再往前一句
- I could not sleep all night.. - No. No. Before that?
對不起，老師
Sorry, sir.
老師！
Sir!
大家都聽到了嗎？
Did everyone hear that?
他管我叫老師
Sir.
傑圖·拜亞已經不是拜亞哥了
Jeetu Bhaiya is no longer a 'Bhaiya' (brother).
我現在是什麼？
What am I now?
老師！
Sir!
不是隻有巴特拉和饒才能叫老師
Batla sir and Rao sir aren't the only sirs.
現在我也能稱什麼……
Even Jeetu Bhaiya is now a..
老師！
Sir!
來，我應該給你點獎勵
You surely deserve a prize.
- 過來-快去
- Come over. - Go. Go
- 來吧-幹得漂亮
- Come. - Well done!
我的成功要歸功於我母親
The credit for my success goes to my mother Mrs.
蘇米特拉
Sumitra..
快去! 去洗洗臉，快去！
Scoot! Go and wash your face. Go!
他想拿走我辛辛苦苦掙來的錢
He wants to take my hard earned money.
- 你翻臉太快了，拜亞哥 -有什麼問題嗎？
- You are so dramatic, Bhaiya. - Why shouldn't I be?
我這個哈拉格佈爾戲劇協會的總管可不是白當的
I wasn't the Governor of Dramatics society IIT Kharagpur for nothing.
讓我們繼續
Let's resume.
-話說有一個漂亮小姐姐 -好的，老師
- A beautiful damsel. - Yes, sir.
一說到小姐姐你們就都精神了
Yes! Now you're all awake.. at the mention of 'damsel'.
- 餡餅新鮮嗎?-當然
- Are the patties fresh, brother? - Certainly.
給我來一個
Give me one.
你怎麼不吃飯，吃餡餅？
You are foregoing food for patties?
這哪是飯，這是垃圾！
It is not food. It is bullcrap!
離家才一個星期你就滿嘴髒話了
Just a week away from home and you've turned foul-mouthed.
垃圾又不是髒話
Bullcrap is not a cuss word.
你就把這當作是身體的必需品
It's a body product.
肥料
Fertilizer.
阿加瓦爾先生曾經在課堂上也說這個詞
Agarwal sir used to utter it even in classroom.
給我來點泡菜
Give me pickle.
你們繼續
Carry on.
烏代，阿加瓦爾先生課上還說要刻苦學習、高度自律
Uday, rather than learning hard work, discipline..
你怎麼就不學點好的
..and punctuality, you choose to learn cuss words from Agarwal sir.
還有你...都吃好幾天餡餅了
And you... Munching patties all the time.
如果你再不好好吃飯，肯定會變得更虛弱
You'll grow weaker if you skip meals.
如果你變得虛弱，你就會生病
If you grow weak you fall ill.
第一周內生病的孩子
And the children who fall ill within the first week..
會被父母帶回家
..are taken back home by their parents.
從此與印度理工無緣
And they never make it to IIT.
米納，我就算吃了這些東西，我也會生病的
Meena, I will fall ill even if I eat this food.
這菜太油膩了
This is so oily.
-這是把賣油的打死了吧?-小聲點
- Is oil free or what? - Speak softly.
如果被錢德魯聽到，我們晚餐就隻能吃拌蔬菜了
If Chandru hears then we'll get mixed vegetables of all the gourds for dinner.
裏麵還有苦瓜
Including bitter gourd.
你還喝上酒了？
Still drinking Bisleri?
米納，這是百歲山，不是牛欄山
Meena. Not Bisleri. Aquafina.
都差不多
It's all the Bisleri's are the same.
你為什麼要浪費錢喝這麼貴的水？
Why are you squandering money? Drink this.
水是無辜的
The mess does not make the water.
這的水都不解渴
My thirst doesn't get quenched by this water.
還有點鹹
It is salty.
- 昌巴爾的水質... 很硬-很硬
- The Chambal water.. Is hard. - Is hard.
我知道
I know.
過去一周我都聽到無數次了
I've been hearing this for the past week.
聽著，如果你吃得不好，你就不能集中註意力
Look, if you don't eat well you won't be able to concentrate.
這樣你就不能長時間學習了
Then you won't be able to study long.
你現在的問題已經夠多了，為什麼還要自找麻煩
As it is you are facing so many complexities why invite a new one.
聽著，如果你一直喝這個，你就會浪費很多錢
Look, if you drink more of this you will spend more money..
如果水喝的少，你就會便秘
..if you drink less you will be constipated.
我已經便秘了
I already am.
你今天還是冇拉出來嗎？
You couldn't empty your bowels even today?
兄弟，我這吃飯呢，聊這個合適嗎？
What kind of conversation is this for the dining table?
你剛才不是還說飯是身體的肥料
Wonderful! When you called this delicious food a body product..
你怎麼不考慮合適不合適？
..was the conversation good then!?
還是拉不出來嗎？
You couldn't empty your bowels?
你要幫他拉嗎？
Are you going empty it for him?
烏代！
Uday!
我們去喝點茶吧
Let's go for some tea.
來吧，寶貝！
Come. Oh, Shivangi!
你咬得太狠了
You bite so hard.
調皮！
Raunchy!
米納
Meena.
我們去喝杯茶吧
Let's go for a tea.
現在還不到5:30
It isn't 5:30 as yet.
你做完這套題了嗎？
Have you finished the sheet?
是的，我做到第35題了
Yes, I've completed up to 35.
你完成了35個？
You completed 35?
你做得好快，我還在做第30題
You did it very fast. I am still on the 30th.
你怎麼不一口氣做完呢?五點半之前要做完
Why don't you complete it? It will be done by 5:30.
你們怎麼能坐這麼久？
How do you guys manage to sit for so long?
我坐一會就纍了
I get tired in a little while.
別這麼說
Don't say that.
昨天你作業都冇做完
Even yesterday you didn't finish the homework.
如果你今天也不做完，那一定會越積越多
If you leave it today as well, it's bound to pile up.
我做不到
I am not up to it.
好好思考一下怎麼合理利用時間
Then try to read the theory. Utilize your time.
我現在不想思考
I don't feel like it now.
這就是我一直想跟你說的
This is what I've been trying to explain to you for so long.
你知道嗎
You know what.
讀讀《火烈鳥》
Read Flamingo for now.
這是一本輕鬆的讀物，能讓為你為考試做好準備
It's a light read and will prepare you for boards too.
拿著
Take it.
裏麵有很多故事
It contains stories.
一隻猴子正在通過滑輪拉下一個物體
A monkey is pulling down an object through a pulley.
另一隻猴子正在拉第一隻猴子的尾巴
Another monkey is pulling the first monkey's tail.
因為它在拉它的尾巴，所以必然會産生緊張的氣氛
Since it is pulling his tail it is bound to create tension.
瓦伊巴夫！
Vaibhav!
你的狀態在我看來完全不對勁
Your symptoms do not appear right to me at all.
你需要一個聰明人的指導
You need the guidance of someone wise.
- 誰?-心理谘詢師
- Who? - A counselor.
心理醫生？
Psychiatrist?
谘詢師? 見鬼去吧！
Counselor? Like hell!
我是精神病嗎? 我抑鬱嗎？
Is this a mental problem? Am I depressed?
我有焦慮癥嗎? 我有自殺傾嚮嗎？
Do I have anxiety? Am I suicidal?
我看起來像是個需要看心理醫生的人嗎？
Have I lost my mind that I need a counselor?
不管怎樣，這裏一多半的谘詢師都是騙子
And anyways, half the counselors here are frauds.
我才不需要谘詢師
I don't need anybody.
你需要阿普唑侖，能提升你的睡眠質量
You need Alprozolam, which is good for your sleep..
可以恢複你體內血清素和多巴胺的平衡
..and can restore the balance of serotonin and dopamine in your body.
乳果糖可以緩解你的便秘問題
And Lactulose for your constipation problems.
門口交費
Pay the fees outside.
你知道你不是醫生吧？
You do know that you are not a Doctor, right?
就因為我穿的實驗服而不是白大褂
Just because I wore a coat instead of an apron..
還有我的字寫得不好，就能說明我不是醫生嗎？
..and my handwriting is not good, does it mean I am not a Doctor?
因為你冇有執照
Because you don't have a license.
你為什麼穿著這件實驗服？
Why have you worn this lab coat?
穿什麼
Don't dress for the job you have.
就是什麼
Dress for the job you want.
瓦伊巴夫
Vaibhav.
我知道你需要什麼了
I know what you need.
克利須那神廟
Radha Krishna temple.
神會聽到你的許願
All your prayers are answered over here.
拿著這個
Take this.
用你最真誠的心寫下你的願望
Write it nicely with a clean heart.
從數學的角度來講這是不可能的，米納
It is mathematically impossible, Meena.
印度理工學院的座位遠不如來這許願的人多
There aren't as many seats in IIT as the number of prayers here.
搞毛線啊，米納？
What is this, Meena?
你為什麼要把我們帶到這裏來？
Why did you have to bring us here?
上帝保佑
Help me.
你瘋了嗎？
Are you crazy?
這是很有必要的
It was needed.
來自一個所愛的人，而不是外人
But not from anybody. A loved one.
一個能夠感同身受的人，一個親身經曆過這一切的人
Someone who would empathize. Someone who has faced this himself.
他跟我說起過你，所以我才帶他來這兒
So, he told me about you. That's why I brought him here.
我來對地方了，不是嗎？
Did the right thing, didn't I?
當然
Absolutely.
你確實很聰明
You certainly are wise.
當然了，他在馬赫什瓦裏教育
Ofcouse, he is in Maheshwari.
皮尤什
Piyush.
快告訴我你是怎麼做到的，兄弟
You tell me how you managed, bro.
我現在吃不好，睡不好，還便秘
My food, drink, potty and sleep, everything is out of order.
你怎麼知道我的地址的？
How did you get my address?
從你的父母那裏
From your parents..
因為你不接我電話
..because you weren't answering my phone.
很聰明，對吧？
Smart, right?
這也是我的主意
Again, my idea.
非常好
Very nice.
我不會佔用你太多時間
I won't take up much of your time.
我能理解馬赫什瓦裏壓力很大
I understand the pressure from Maheshwari.
跟我分享一下你的應對機製吧
Just share with me any coping mechanism.
我實在受不了了
I am not able to handle it.
患難見真情，對吧？
A friend in need is a friend indeed, right?
對吧，兄弟？
Isn't that right, brother?
你真是來對地方了
You did the right thing coming here?
難道不是嗎？
Ain't that true?
謝謝你
Thank you.
太對了
You did the right thing..
因為我也受不了了
..because even I am unable to handle it.
看來皮尤什也便秘了
It seems even Piyush is constipated.
不是一回事，兄弟
This is something else, Meena.
怎麼了，兄弟？
What's the matter, bro?
我不在馬赫什瓦裏
I am not in Maheshwari.
在過去的六個月裏，我一直在上私教
I've been taking individual lessons for the past six months.
我的猜測是對的，米納
My suspicion turned out right, Meena.
我跟你說過
Didn't I tell you,
為什麼一個‘馬赫什瓦裏’的學生會住在塔萬迪薩博，而不是維根納加爾
what is a 'Maheshwari' boy doing in Talwandi instead of Vigyan Nagar.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你在說什麼？
What are you saying?
我爸是托關係才給我送進馬赫什瓦裏的
Dad got me admitted using influence..
但是第一次考試之後我就被排到後麵的分組了
..but when the batch was shuffled after the first test..
最後一組
..I ended up in the last batch.
第二次考試我又是最後一組的倒數第一
The next time I was the last student in that batch as well.
然後我不得不退學，選擇上私教
Then I had to leave Maheshwari and opt for individual coaching.
我明白了
I see.
這就是你不回我電話的原因，你這個無賴
That's why you wouldn't return my calls, you rascal.
- 對不起，兄弟 - 滾蛋
- So sorry, brother. - Get lost!
你要我怎麼開口？
How could I tell you?
爸爸在老家到處吹噓
Dad has bragged all over Itarsi..
我在馬赫什瓦裏教育
..that I am in Maheshwari.
是啊
Ya.
他確實愛吹牛
He does brag alot.
他在老家跟所有人說我冇被馬赫什瓦裏錄取
He told all of Itarsi that I didn't get admitted to Maheshwari.
老家親戚朋友都認為我一定能考上印度理工
All of Itarsi feels I will surely get admitted to IIT.
是的，我們都有這種感覺
Yes. All of us feel that way.
是的
Yes.
我還很納悶他的成績是怎麼突然飆上來的
I was baffled as to how he soared so suddenly.
我希望你的家人知道
I hope your family knows.
- 不行，兄弟 - 不行？
- No, buddy. - No?
上次我回家的時候
Last time when I went home for Diwali..
我本來打算把一切都說出來，結束這件事，但是……
..I had planned on disclosing everything and end the matter but..
但是？
But?
這是我有生以來第一次接到尼哈打來的電話
For the first time in my life Neha called.
尼哈 · 普羅希特？
Neha Purohit?
是的，你認識她的妹妹
Yes. You know her younger sister.
- 希爾帕?-是的
- Shilpa? - Yes.
她也想考印度理工學院，需要我的建議
She was thinking of IIT herself and needed tips from me.
所以他們兩個都來了我家
So both of them came to my place.
尼哈和希爾帕？
Both Neha and Shilpa?
- 是的-還有他們的媽媽也來了
- Yes. - Their mom came too.
- 迪莎阿姨?-是的
- Aunt Disha? - Yes.
這是我有生以來第一次得到如此多的認可
For the first time in my life I got so much recognition..
我怎麼能就這麼算了呢？
..how could I have let it go?
還有，你知道嗎，在談話中
Also, do you know, during the conversation..
阿姨還跟我確認了我的出生日期和時間
..aunt confirmed my time and date of birth.
我也在為印度理工學院做準備啊
Even I am preparing for IIT.
我在學校成績還比你好
I was a better student than you in school.
她怎麼不來找我要建議
She never asked me for tips.
因為你在神童教育
You are studying in Prodigy.
先不說那些了，快幫我想想辦法
Never mind all of that. Tell me what I should do.
你啊
You..
最好去看看心理醫生
..better see a counselor.
餵，媽媽
Yes, mummy.
你在幹什麼？
What were you doing?
冇什麼，我在學習
Nothing. Was studying when..
然後一位無所事事的女士打擾了我
..an idle lady disturbed me.
她怎麼能這麼做？
How could she do that?
在你學習的時候你要跟你房東說清楚，不要來打擾……
Make it clear to your landlady when you are studying she..
我知道了
I got it.
我掛了，你繼續學習吧
I'll hang up. You continue studying.
你心情怎麼樣？
Are you in a good spirit?
可好了，放心吧
Yes, mummy. I am.
除非我明確告訴你，否則就不要自己亂猜
Until I categorically tell you never assume otherwise.
好吧，晚安
Well, goodnight.
晚安
Goodnight.
什麼意思？
What do you mean?
“我冇做這道題，因為我看不懂”
"I didn't attempt the problem as I didn't understand it."
一定要尋找線索，題幹裏麵給出了很多線索
Always look for hints, so many are there.
在哪呢？
Where?
第一個提示就是這道題是人出的
The first hint is that the problem is given.
當出題者嚮我們提出問題時
When the maker has posed the problem to us..
這就意味著利用我們現有的知識是可以解決的
..that means it's solvable with our knowledge.
另外速度也給了
Secondly the velocity is given.
看到了吧，是不是？
See. Is it or isn't it?
那麼速度隻有在兩種情況下會用到
So, it will be used in either of the two things.
能量或動量
Energy or momentum.
現在你要決定賭一把
Now you have to decide which gamble to take.
如果你還是冇看懂，那麼繼續尋找線索
If it still doesn't make sense then keep looking for hints.
“摩擦”這個詞看到了嗎？
Is the word 'friction' visible?
是的
Yes.
這意味著不是能量
It means energy cannot be used.
那還剩什麼了? 動量守恆
What does that leave? Conservation of momentum.
初始值等於最終值
Initial equal to final.
回答是或不是
Say yes or no.
是的
Yes, sir.
隻需要把初始值和最終值等同起來
Just equate initial to final.
打勾然後看下一題
Tick it and move on.
在未來的某個時刻，可能在你開心的唱歌時
At some point in the future whilst laughing, singing..
或者在上廁所時，你就會意識到
..or in toilet you will realize..
為什麼動量是守恆的
..why was the momentum conserved.
好嗎？
Okay?
即使你不理解這個問題，你也要解題
Even if you don't understand the question jostle with it.
你是做什麼的？
What do you do?
解題的
Jostle with it.
是的
Yes.
一旦你學會了解題和轉筆
Once you have learned to jostle with questions and twirl the pen...
你就已經是半個理工學院人了
..you are already half an IITian.
來吧下一題
Come on. Next.
你要去哪，剩下的題你不做了嗎？
Hello, bro. Didn't you do the rest?
老師，我隻做到了52題
Sir, I only did up to number 52.
我明白了，你做了52道題，非常棒！
I see. You completed 52. Very good!
我這人就是不愛護環境
It's me who hates the environment.
我印150道題就是為了浪費紙，對吧？
I made a 150 page long sheet just to waste paper, right?
不是我不能解題
Sir, Not that I can't crack problems..
而是我坐不住闆凳
..but I am unable to sit for long.
我心情不好
I'm not in the right spirit.
這是真的嗎，還是另有隱情？
Is this the problem or there's more to it?
拜亞哥，他來了之後吃不好
Bhaiya, he doesn't even eat well.
他靠吃餡餅生存
He survives on Maggi and patties.
他每天喝礦泉水，甚至都不怎麼睡覺
He still drinks Bisleri water and doesn't even sleep.
真的嗎？
Why, brother?
是的，拜亞哥
Yes, Bhaiya.
你來的比別人晚
You came late.
所以錯過了迎新會
So he missed the orientation.
他不知道在科塔生活的兩個重要概念
He does not know the two important concepts of living in Kota.
告訴他，米娜爾
Tell him, Meenal.
兩個什麼概念？
What are they?
首先，傑圖·拜亞不是我們的物理教員
Firstly, Jeetu Bhaiya is not our physics faculty.
他是我們的知心姐姐
He is our agony aunt.
能解決各種各樣的問題
He solves all kinds of problems.
學術問題，非學術問題，個人問題，經濟問題或者感情問題
Academic, non-academic, personal, financial or romantic.
即使你半夜喝多了
Even if your landlord has kicked you out of the house..
被房東趕出來
..in the middle of the night or if you've argued with the mess people..
或者是被警察抓到你看黃色雜誌
..or if a Policeman has caught you reading obscene literature.
傑圖·拜亞都能解決
Jeetu Bhaiya solves everything.
隻要給他打電話，傑圖·拜亞就能幫助你
Just call him immediately and Jeetu Bhaiya solves all the problems.
還有
And..
第二個？
..the second?
你忘了第二個？
You forgot the second?
是的
Yes.
"每個孩子都是特別的"
Every child is special.
這完全是胡說八道
That is utter nonsense.
你不是什麼獨一無二的人
You are not some unique personality.
你遇到的問題每年都會發生在成仟上萬的學生身上
These problems occur to thousands of students each year.
在準備去理工學院生活之前，你必須學會在科塔生存
Before preparing for IIT at Kota one must prepare themselves to live in Kota.
有很多簡單的方法可以做到
And there are simple ways to do it.
如果你遇到問題
If you encounter problems..
解決問題
Jostle with them.
即使你不喜歡這裏的水，也要喝
Even if you don't like the water, Just drink it.
即使你不喜歡這些亂七八糟的食物，也要吃
Even if you don't like the mess food, Just eat it.
即使你不能長時間地坐著，也要一直坐著
Even if you are unable to sit for long Just sit for long.
挑戰你自己，我會坐很久
Challenge yourself. I will sit for long.
我根本起不來
I won't get up at all.
我要解題，我要讀書
I will solve problems. I will read theories.
我要看講座
I will watch Unacademy's lessons.
我要複習以前的錯題
I will go through old papers.
我會睡覺，我會死，但我就是不會站起來
I will sleep, I will die but I won't get up.
這樣的話，你做到了什麼？
So, what have you done?
你已經把你遇到的問題轉化為勇氣
You have turned your problems to dare.
而勇氣則與自我直接相關
And dare is directly connected to ego.
自我有許多缺點，但它也有優點
Ego has many disadvantages but it has one advantage too.
事情似乎是可行的
Things seem to be doable.
你不必長時間強迫自己去做這些事情
And you don't have to do this drama for long.
多少天？
How many days?
21天
21 days.
你可以在21天內養成或放棄任何習慣
You can form any or give up any habit in 21 days.
我以前抽煙很兇
I had a smoking problem.
一天兩包
2 packs a day.
我戒掉了
I lost it.
戒煙之後我就在家裏炫耀
I left it one day and after that I bragged about it at home..
給我的女朋友，同事，司機和司機的妻子炫耀
..to my girlfriend, faculty, driver and the driver's wife.
因此，我給了那個小販2000盧比
So much so, I gave 2000 rupees to the vendor..
不要把煙賣給我
..not to give me cigarettes to smoke.
如果你嚮全世界吹噓，那麼世界就不會讓你吸煙
If you brag about it to the world then the world won't let you smoke.
剛開始戒煙的時候我很難受，很想抽煙
I felt a little urge in the beginning and then some more.
但是過了21天，這種欲望就冇有了
By the time 21 days had passed the urge was zero.
這就是你必須做的
That's what you have to do.
說點什麼，是或不是
Say something. Yes or no.
是的，拜亞哥
Yes, Bhaiya.
烏代是個討厭的家夥
Uday is a nasty fella..
但是米納，你明知道你的朋友會這樣
..but Meena, you knew this was happening with your friend..
但你還是冇告訴他？
..and still didn't tell him?
拜亞哥，我……
Bhaiya, I..
你也一樣，佈魯圖斯
You too, Brutus.
你也一樣
You too.
你註意到了嗎？
Did you notice?
拜亞哥叫我佈魯圖斯，‘佈魯圖斯·米納’
Bhaiya called me Brutus. 'Brutus Meena'
幹嘛? 你冇有一點幽默感嗎？
What? Don't you have any sense of humour?
我很醜，但是我很溫柔
I might look nasty but not from the heart.
當然，我是比哈爾猛虎的成員
Sure, I'm a member of the Bihar Tigers.
我肩負著整個城市和平
I have the responsibility of the entire city on these shoulders.
但是烏代 · 古普塔絕不會忽視他的朋友
But Uday Gupta never ignores his sidekicks.
因為你哥我是街頭之王
..because your brother is the king of the streets.
我已經開啓了'非學術'的年度訂閱
I have taken the annual subscription for Unacademy plus.
給你開的
For you.
去吧，想聽多少講座就聽多少
Go. Attend as many live lectures as you wish.
永遠記住，你的兄弟是我，不是佈魯圖斯
And always remember. Your brother is Caesar, not Brutus.
他下午三點才起床
This man rises up at 3 pm.
但是你不要起來，去學習
But don't you rise. Go study.
你在看什麼? 快去學習
What are you looking at? Go study.
人不會討厭他看不見的東西
One cannot hate what one does not see.
完全不要看那些亂七八糟的食物
Don't look at the mess food at all.
不慌不忙地撕一塊麵包
Pick up bread without a fuss.
隨便蘸點什麼，嚼嚼就行了
Dip it in whatever and just chew.
有時你可能會忍不住下看
Sometimes you may be tempted to look down..
但這就是你的失敗之處
..but therein lies your defeat.
今天味道好多了
Tastes even better today.
不要喝常溫的水
Don't drink water at room temperature.
喝冰箱裏的冷水
Drink chilled water of the fridge.
人們甚至覺得冰鎮啤酒都好喝
People even savour beer if chilled.
鹽水算不了什麼
Salt water is nothing.
幹杯
Bottoms up.
這裏的 x 錶示塊的距離
Here x is given as the distance of the block..
我們必須找到速度作為 x 的函數
..and we have to find the velocity as a function of x.
隻要選擇正確的選項
Just choose the correct option.
C.
你什麼時候來的？
When did you come?
我來看看你
I came to check on you.
很好! 很好！
Good! Good!
如果你選擇了 c 選項，那麼你的答案是正確的
If you have chosen C option then your answer is correct.
現在我來告訴你這個問題的解決辦法
Now I shall tell you the solution of this question.
是的，我吃過了
Yes, I have eaten.
我很好，精神也很好
I am all well and am in good spirits.
媽媽，你怎麼能每天都問我同樣的問題呢？
Mummy, how do you manage to keep repeating the same question everyday?
好吧
Okay.
再用點力，兄弟
Apply more pressure, bro.
瓦伊巴夫
Vaibhav.
有用嗎？
Is it working?
扁豆湯，蔬菜和麵包都準備好
Lentil soup, veggies and breads have to be prepared..
所以總會有一個錯誤範圍
..so there is always a scope of mistake.
在這樣的範圍內，廚師們肯定會犯錯誤
Given the scope, the cooks in the mess ensure mistakes.
這就是為什麼一個人應該更喜歡吃自己不做的東西
That's why one should prefer eating what they don't make..
例如沙拉，泡菜，薄餅，酸奶和糖
..such as salad, pickle, papad, yogurt and sugar.
這樣你的套餐就做好了
And there is your three course meal.
我治好了很多人的便秘
I have helped many people crap.
你的也一樣
Yours is no different.
兩口
Two puffs.
隻要兩口
Only two puffs.
你就能體驗到飛一般的感覺
You will experience streamline motion.
完全冇有摩擦力
Not friction.
胡說八道
Nonsense.
-拿著，這是“真相”-滾開! 該死的癮君子！
Take it. This is 'the truth'. -Scram! Bloody addict!
孩子們，今天我們要解決一個關於垂直圓周運動的問題
Children, today we shall solve a problem on vertical circular motion.
讓我先給你解釋一下這個問題
Let me first explain the problem to you.
瓦伊巴夫
Vaibhav.
房東阿姨
Aunty.
她走下樓梯時摔倒了
She was walking down the stairs and fell.
口吐白沫
She is frothing in the mouth.
你好，我需要救護車
Hello. Ambulance.
快來拉爾 · 伯奇酒店，非常緊急
Come to Lal Burj quickly. It's an emergency.
什麼? 泡沫? 哪裏？
What? Froth? Where?
這就起來了？
You got up?
為了那個老巫婆？
For that two-bit woman?
你隻是想找個理由站起來
You just want an excuse.
去你的吧！
Damn you!
你會在拜亞哥麵前給我們帶來恥辱
You will bring disgrace on us in Jeetu Bhaiya's presence.
把賭註裏的100盧比給我
Give me my 100 rupees from the bet.
工程師
Engineer.
大自然已經完成了一半的工作
Nature has done half the job.
水含有鹽分
Water contains salt.
隻要加鹽和檸檬就行了
Just add salt and lemon to it.
這樣檸檬水就做好了
Lemonade is ready.
這個小知識每年拯救一仟萬兒童的生命
This small tip saves ten million children's lives every year.
太棒了！
It's great!
不是嗎？
Isn't it?
現在去拿兩個杯子
Go and prepare two glasses now.
三個
Three.
媽媽，烏代的女朋友給烏代打電話的次數，遠冇有你給我打電話的次數多
Mummy, Uday's girlfriend does not call him as many times as you call me.
走! 走! 走! 快點！
Go! Go! Go! Come on!
幹得好，兄弟! 幹得好！
Well done, bro! Well done!
你就快進入印度理工了，加油
You are under the oath of IIT.
如果連一天都堅持不下來，那還怎麼看闆球比賽？
One can't follow one days, how will one follow test cricket?
T-20版本是專為科塔學生設計的
The T-20 format has been created for Kota students.
IPL（印度超級闆球聯賽）是未來的趨勢
IPL is the future.
要是他們能讓尤弗拉伊上場就好了
If only they would take Yuvraj to play.
那就大錯特錯了
It's very wrong of them.
你說得對，兄弟，這都是政治手段
You are correct, bro. It's all politics.
兄弟，尤維可以，絕對行
Bro, Yuvi can and Yuvi will.
冇錯，兄弟，尤弗拉伊會回來的
That's right, bro. Yuvraj will return.
記住我說的話
You can quote me on that.
你覺得呢？
You?
是的
Yes.
他會回來的
He will return.
孩子們，今天我們要解決一個關於沖量動量定理的問題
Children, today we shall solve a problem on impulse momentum theorem
在這節課中，我們將學習計算推動力
In it we shall learn to calculate impulse.
哇! 今天一點聲音都冇有
Wow! There was no sound today.
你知道你這樣真的很變態吧
You know this is really inappropriate.
我為你感到高興，兄弟
I'm happy for you, buddy.
孩子們，我們今天要解決一個關於摩擦力的問題
Children, we will solve a problem on friction today.
正如你在圖片中看到的那樣，有兩個木塊
As you can see in the picture two blocks are made.
這兩個木塊都放在一個楔子上
Both the blocks are kept on a wedge
兩者都是用一根繩子連接起來的
..and both are connected with the help of a string.
blah blah blah…
[Educator speaking]
走吧？
Shall we?
已經六點半了
It is 6:30 already.
我們走
Let's go.
貼近理工學院的一小步
One step closer to IIT
這些是在課堂上完成的
That was done in class.
但我很高興你今天把作業做完了
But I'm glad today you came with DPP and sheets finished.
這就意味著你完全可以坐得更久
That means this chap is able to sit up longer.
是的
Yes, sir.
飲食問題解決了嗎？
Is food and water sorted?
是的，拜亞哥
Yes, Bhaiya.
你能正常拉屎了嗎？
Are you able to crap properly?
哦，兄弟！
Oh, Bhaiya!
來吧，你為什麼對我這麼害羞？
Come along. Why are you being shy with me?
我是你的知心大姐
I am your agony aunt.
我們還有很長的路要走
And we have a long journey together.
每個人都會有這樣那樣的問題
Everyone has these problems.
我也有
I too have them.
你學過物理化學嗎？
Have you been doing Physical Chemistry?
給我根煙
Give me one.
香煙？
A cigarette?
是的
Yes.
你不是戒煙了嗎？
Cigarette, Bhaiya?
當我感受不到刺激，情況在我掌控之中的時候
When I don't feel the urge and the situation is under control..
也是可以作弊的
..then you can cheat sometimes.
偶爾作弊是可以的
Cheating occasionally is fine.
但不要經常作弊
As long as it doesn't become a habit.
- 怎麼了?-摩托車！
- What's the matter? - Auto!
趕緊去維根納加爾
Lets rush to Vigyan Nagar.
- 我們走，先生-拜亞哥！
- Let's go, sir. - Bhaiya!
- 拜亞哥!-回頭見
- Bhaiya! - I'll see you later.
發生了什麼？
What happened?
大自然的召喚？
Nature's call?
是的
Yes.
米納
Meena.
來吧
Come.
現在才5點
It's only 5 O'clock.
我們走! 快！
Let's go! Come!
書又不會跑
It's always the same..
我們走！
Let's go!
讓我把這段看完
I just needed to study one more paragraph.
這段學完會怎樣嗎？
What will you gain from studying one paragraph?
拜亞哥說了
Jeetu Bhaiya said so.
偶爾作弊是可以的
Occasional cheating is fine.
隻要不養成習慣
As long as you don't form a habit.
您撥打的電話無人接聽
'The person you are calling is not answering.
請稍後再試”
Please try later.'
他不接我電話
He's not picking my call.
他現在在一個快樂的地方
Now he is in a happy place.